[theme music playing]
As long as I'm in power,
no traitor or rebel
can ever bring the Ardientes down!
[William] That arrogance of theirs
will lead that family to their downfall.
Where are the earnings
from the gambling den?
We have yet to reach
our quota, Congressman.
Just disappear, and don't come back
until I tell you to do so.
Go ahead, Ardientes. Keep belittling me.
I'll drain all your wealth.
[Natalie] Everyone comes back
for a reason.
I still think about how my dad died.
I know someone had him killed,
and I want to know who it is.
-I'll talk. I'm going to talk.
-[Julio] What was that?
I'm going to talk!
-Give me the answer I want.
-The governor.
-Who?
-Alvarez.
[Diego] As long as the Ardientes
are in power,
they can't be brought down.
Someone should fight them head-on.
I'll run for governor.
I will do everything
in my power to help you win.
Sue Governor Alvarez,
and I'll tell you where he is.
[Julio] You are of no use now, Madrigal.
Adios. Go ahead! Do it!
Lower your guns.
We'll use him as a witness
against Alvarez.
Good thing I caught up with you
before you escaped your crimes.
If you're talking about
the spare change I took,
that's nothing compared
to the wealth you all stole.
Alvarez is out, and Emilia is so in!
I, Diego Ardiente-Torillo,
will run as governor of our town
in the next election.
-Go, Diego!
-You'll run for governor?
Once I become governor, I will
be the most powerful Ardiente.
Everyone will bow to the king,
and you will be my queen.
Diego.
Here are the contacts you asked for.
This will help you find
volunteers for your campaign.
Thank you.
You have no idea how thankful
I am to you, Diego.
For helping Lily save Jepoy
from the Ardientes,
despite how close they are to each other.
I know how important Jepoy is to Ivy.
But I'll do everything to help her.
If I could keep her from
ever seeing the Ardientes again,
I would.
I know this is hard for her too.
That goes for me too, Diego.
But if this is how Lily wants to do it…
we have to be there to support her.
And I hope, Diego, you won't let go.
Because Lily's heart
belongs to you and only to you.
I know.
This is just another sacrifice
we have to make.
We have to make
to achieve change in our town.
Um, Papa, it's been days
since the Alvarez fiasco,
and you still haven't appointed
an acting governor.
Don't you think it's about time
you reinstate me?
Everyone thinks you're sick, remember?
Papa, have I still not proven
my capabilities to you?
I will not reinstate you.
There, I've said it. Satisfied?
But, Papa, you have to face
the fact that in no time…
you'll be gone. And as early as now,
I have to be in office
to maintain our family's legacy.
Two things.
First, you're wrong.
You're very wrong because
I am going to live forever.
Secondly,
Arnaldo will run for
governor of Poblacion Ardiente
in the next election, and not you.
Well, that's a good decision
because I don't care
what the feminists say.
Clearly, politics is not
a place for women.
I agree. They all belong in the kitchen.
And between you and Emilia,
I will choose you as governor.
Notwithstanding, of course,
your wrong choices in women.
We're talking about Ivy now. Okay.
I'll prove she's the right choice.
And while I'm at it, I'll also prove
that I will be the best governor
this town could ever have.
Ouch.
[Jepoy] You got everything
you want from me.
I'm no good now.
Let me go!
You can leave this place
if you'll do what I say.
You ratted Alvarez out.
That was the beginning.
Now, you're just going to finish
what you started.
It's simple. Another's head
in exchange for yours, Madrigal.
Bring me Alvarez's head…
and I'll set you free.
I won't do what you want.
Well, then. I'll be outside, just in case.
Now, if you're ready to talk to me,
you can tell any of my men here.
Just don't think of running away.
Because my men won't hesitate to kill you.
I'm not afraid to die.
[chuckles]
You can't fool me.
Everybody's afraid to die.
You most of all.
You, who went through so much trouble.
You gave me Alvarez just so
I wouldn't kill you.
You value your life too much,
more than anything else.
Oh, and there's one more thing
that you value.
Your freedom.
Now, you will kill Alvarez…
in exchange for your life and freedom.
[ominous music playing]
Hurry! Get that out of here!
This one too. That one.
That belongs to the police
blotter and not in this office!
Hurry!
Are you sure Julio isn't going
to mind what you're doing?
Of course not, Aunt Claire.
I'll inch my way back to this
position by hook or by crook.
Because I am preparing
my comeback as the queen.
The queen?
My dear, there's going to be a new king.
And I'm pretty sure
he will have his own queen.
Emilia, you're slowly being eased out.
[line ringing]
Hello, Martinez?
Talk to the private investigator,
and find out more about Ivy Aguas.
I will not be pushed
to the sidelines, Auntie.
Especially once I prove to my family
that Ivy Aguas is connected
to Camia Cruz and Madrigal.
And when that happens,
I'll be the hero of the family.
Oh. How I miss this chair.
[chuckles]
[ominous music playing]
And what if I refuse again?
I have my men watching your every move.
They know every decision you make.
And if you change your mind
and think of escaping…
or even if you go slightly off-target…
I have snipers ready
to blow your brains out.
But then again, I'm sure you
wouldn't want that, would you?
I wouldn't want to do that.
Well?
Hmm.
Silence means yes.
Good boy.
Good boy, Madrigal. Go and get him.
And, please…
don't disappoint me.
[elevator chimes]
[ominous music playing]
[phone ringing]
Hello?
Yeah? Where's the chopper?
What's taking you so long?
I've been waiting here. Hurry!
[doorbell chimes]
Hold on.
[tense music playing]
[grunts]
[groans]
[thuds]
[grunts]
[tense music playing]
[groans]
Alvarez!
Stay away from me!
I know Julio sent you.
Don't come any closer!
Don't let the Ardientes
control you, Madrigal.
You don't have to do this.
[grunts]
[groans]
[grunting]
[screams]
[thuds]
[ominous music playing]
Governor William Alvarez was found dead
at the Pacific Winds Hotel.
According to multiple witness statements,
there's a possibility of foul play.
Let's interview one of the witnesses.
[woman] I saw the governor with
a man on the hotel rooftop.
He was wearing a cap
and looked pretty tall.
It looked like he
and the governor were fighting.
Then, I saw the governor
jump down from the building.
It's Jepoy.
I'm sure they're referring to him.
Those wretched Ardientes!
They forced Jepoy
to kill Governor Alvarez.
They're monsters!
But, Lily, if Jepoy was ordered
to kill Alvarez,
the Ardientes might set him free now.
[clapping]
Job well done, Madrigal!
Come here. Join me.
Drink with me. Drink with me.
Okay.
This is yours. Okay?
To your health!
I don't need that. We had an agreement.
You said you'd set me free.
Let me go! Let me go now!
[clicks tongue]
What's the rush?
Cheers.
For your freedom,
and for your nearing encounter
with the devil or Grim Reaper,
whoever comes first.
No. You don't know the Ardientes.
They're all cunning…
Grandpa, Mom, and Arnaldo.
What are you trying to say?
They might let Jepoy live
as long as he's useful to them.
-And if he isn't?
-They'll kill him.
You know, I don't need you anymore.
You are useless.
I can give you the freedom you want,
but let's play a game first.
We're now going to play a game
called Russian roulette.
One bullet.
Six chambers.
This is how the game goes.
I'll spin the gun's cylinder,
and then aim it at your forehead.
If I pull the trigger and it fires…
I'm sorry, you're dead.
If not, we'll do it over again.
Watch.
Okay.
No! Don't! No!
[groans]
As I said, I know you value your
life more than anything else.
Ready?
Hmm? Any last words?
-Huh?!
-[gun clicks]
-You bastard!
-[laughs]
You evil bastard! You lied to me!
You don't keep your word, you bastard!
That's enough. Enough!
-Honestly, Madrigal.
-You're insane!
Do you think I'm a fool?
Do you think I'm insane?
I tell you what, Madrigal.
I have full control of my faculties.
It's just that I love playing this game!
[laughs]
Hey!
Get him out of here. I'm tired.
-Let's go!
-[grunts]
[Julio] I'm sick and tired of this game.
[laughing]
I'm not crazy, Madrigal. I'm not crazy.
I won't allow that to happen to Jepoy.
Wait. Where are you going?
I'll go to the Ardientes
and save my friend.
You can't leave.
You can't stop me.
I need to save Jepoy. Get out of my way.
-No. I won't.
-What's wrong with you?
I'll do it! I'll save him. Not you.
You are not going to do that.
I'm his friend, so I'll be
the one to save Jepoy.
-I know. He's your friend.
-Diego!
-Listen to me!
-Diego, stop!
Yes, he's your friend, but I love you!
If you get caught, you're done for.
It will be the end of you and our fight.
But I'll die first before that happens.
Ivy, I won't allow you
to put yourself in danger.
Ivy.
Ivy, trust me. I'll get Jepoy back.
I'll bring him back safe and sound.
I promise.
Here. Fix yourself up.
So you'll look presentable
when you're six feet under.
[ominous music playing]
I'll do everything to protect you.
Until my last breath.
[ominous music playing]
[huffing]
Ivy, Jepoy already
accomplished his mission.
Why hasn't he come back yet?
Why does Julio still have him?
If I could just ask Congressman
to let go of Jepoy,
I'll do it, Ivy.
No, Nanny. You can't do that.
I don't want you
to put yourself in danger.
I'm worried about Jepoy too.
But Diego promised me
that he would save him.
All right, Ivy.
Can you believe that?
Governor Alvarez is dead.
I know. Anyway, I'll go charge my phone.
-Sure.
-Okay.
But hurry up, I'll be alone here.
Okay. Sure, sure.
[groans]
[thuds]
[tense music playing]
[grunts]
[metal clanking]
Jepoy! Jepoy. It's me, Diego!
Jepoy, it's me!
[grunts]
[clattering]
Jepoy, I'm Diego!
It's Diego!
[grunting]
No, don't! Don't take it off,
there are cameras!
There are cameras here.
-Jepoy--
-What are you doing here?
Jepoy, I'm busting you out of here.
We're going to escape.
Jepoy!
[gunshots]
[clattering]
[grunting]
[clinks]
Let's go!
-Jepoy! Jepoy! Mom!
-Ivy.
-Jepoy!
Here. Bring him here.
Jepoy!
-Jepoy! Jepoy!
-Jepoy!
You're back! You're back home!
What happened? What did they do to you?
I'm glad you're all right!
Jepoy, what happened to you?
Ivy, Diego's been shot!
Diego!
Guards!
Diego, what happened? Guards, help me!
Diego!
Guards, here.
Quick!
Mom! Nanny! I need a towel.
-Carlotta!
-Get me water, quick!
Diego, what happened?
-Auntie.
-Here it is, dear.
Mom, I need to remove the bullet.
[groans]
Diego. Diego. Diego.
Nanny, please call a doctor! Please!
-[Diego grunts]
-[Ivy] Diego.
I've sent the doctor home.
Jepoy, I've arranged for you
to stay at the rest house.
That won't be necessary, Ivy.
What do you mean?
Jepoy, I'm sure the Ardientes
are looking for you.
-You have to hide.
-I know that.
You're right, I need to hide.
But not at your rest house.
I can't stay there.
Jepoy, what do you mean?
As long as I'm connected with Ivy,
the Ardientes will continue
to be suspicious of her.
Ivy, I'm the key.
I'm the time bomb
they're waiting on to explode
so they'll find out who you really are.
If you hide me in your rest house…
the danger of them discovering
your real plans will persist.
Jepoy…
Ivy, they'll find out you're Lily.
I have to cut ties with you.
I have to go away.
I have to stay away from you, Ivy.
[slow instrumental playing]
If not for you, something worse
might've happened to Jepoy.
He's important to you.
So I helped him escape.
Ivy, I'll do everything…
everything to make
you happy because I love you.
Even if you love me or not…
my feelings for you will never change.
No matter what.
This isn't the right time, Diego.
I know.
I'll wait for you.
[slow instrumental playing]
[Jepoy] Ivy, my time is running out.
Julio Ardiente will kill me.
If not now, maybe tomorrow.
[Jepoy] May I have some coffee?
[woman] Be right there.
[Jepoy] I need to stay away from you.
As long as the Ardientes are after me…
there's the threat of them
discovering that you are Lily.
[police officer]
Are you done preparing this?
I'll get it now, okay?
-Okay.
-Here you go.
[Jepoy] Even if I'm not with you…
I know that Diego is there for you.
He'll love you like I love you.
Maybe even more.
Yours, Jepoy.
I'm supposed to give
a commemorative speech
for the death of Alvarez.
But why would I honor that traitor?
I understand.
But the way I see it…
I can use the venue
to announce my candidacy.
Good thinking!
Let's not waste that opportunity, then.
And let's do this to reinforce the fact…
that no one can go against the Ardientes.
[knocks on door]
[Julio] Hey!
Who said you could barge in like that?!
I'm sorry, Congressman.
But Madrigal escaped.
Darn it!
Jepoy left without even saying
goodbye to me.
We didn't get the chance to talk, Ivy.
Nanny.
I didn't say goodbye.
Carlotta.
Camia, I treated Jepoy like my own.
What if he gets in trouble? What if…
What if they find him, Ivy?
The Ardientes will kill him!
I know where you're coming from.
But he decided this on his own.
He has his reasons.
We both know Jepoy.
He can take care of himself.
Diego's right, Carlotta.
It'll be hard for me
to respect his decision.
But I'm certain he did that
for Ivy's safety.
[Julio screaming]
Idiots! Morons!
You bunch of imbeciles!
Can one of you explain to me
how exactly someone tortured to near death
managed to escape you?!
You have eyes, don't you?! You have feet!
Your problem is, you don't have brains!
[gunshot]
Papa, I think Ivy Aguas
had something to do with this.
Can you please stop
dragging Ivy into this mess?
Arnaldo, I have proof
that Madrigal and Ivy are accomplices.
Shut up, Emilia.
You, Domingo.
Did you see who helped Madrigal escape?
No, Congressman. He was wearing a mask.
But we're sure it was a guy.
You're sure it was a guy?
[gunshot]
Miss Carlotta…
Ivy, I have to go.
Okay, Diego.
Diego…
Thank you so much.
Thank you for saving Jepoy.
I'll be upstairs.
I'll be there in a bit.
I told you I'd do anything for you.
For the people important to you.
You should get some rest.
I hope you'll feel a little
better tomorrow morning.
This will last the whole night.
But tomorrow, we fight again.
Take care.
Ivy, wait.
I hope you don't take this
the wrong way but…
Is it okay if I sleep here?
Why?
I want to protect you.
[knocks on door]
Diego--
Uh…
I brought you some extra sheets.
Thanks.
It's a good thing you're here.
Because to be honest,
I'm still worried for you.
I'm glad you're here
so we can protect each other.
I can't imagine what will happen when…
you're face-to-face with the Ardientes,
especially when you run for governor.
You're worried about me?
You're like a lamb in a cage of lions
when you're with the Ardientes.
What if they discover your plans
and find out who you really are?
I'm only human, Diego.
I get hurt and angry.
When I'm with the Ardientes,
I can't help but loathe them more.
But I need to do this,
to pretend, to befriend them…
so I can bring them down.
Ivy…
We can live a simple life.
Why do we have to do this?
I can't afford a simple life, Diego.
Because I won't be able to forgive myself
if I don't do anything
about the Ardientes.
If they don't pay for what they've done.
Go on, get some rest.
Ivy…
["Sa'Yo" instrumental playing]
Ivy, I promise you…
that I'll be here to fight
for you no matter what.
["Sa'Yo" by Silent Sanctuary playing]
[phone ringing]
Yes, Mr. Mayor?
Mr. Mayor?
Mr. Mayor, I came as soon as I heard.
-Sit down.
-I can't believe it.
How'd Madrigal manage to escape?
Maybe because he had
an accomplice within our circle?
No, Mom.
The guards said somebody rescued him.
But there's no need to worry.
Our men are looking for him
and his accomplice.
That's why we had to push back
the commemoration
and the program at the town hall.
Because we have to devote all our time
to catch Madrigal right away.
Congressman, isn't it more
important to push through
with the public address
instead of looking for Madrigal?
Why don't you use the event tomorrow
to spread the word
about the search for Madrigal?
[Arnaldo] Why not?
I think she has a point.
Why don't we follow the original schedule,
and then let's instruct our men
to initiate a full-blown manhunt
for Madrigal.
What do you think, Grandpa?
[Ivy sighs]
How did Madrigal even escape?
And who helped him?
[Martinez] Ma'am.
Ma'am.
My goodness, Martinez. Out of nowhere.
You're going to give me a heart attack.
Ma'am, I have the files you asked for
from your private investigator.
[Martinez] Excuse me.
[suspenseful music playing]
[tense music playing]
[Arnaldo] Okay, I would like
to propose a toast
for Ardiente's very special woman.
Ivy Aguas.
For all the help you've given our family.
-Cheers.
Once again, Miss Aguas,
thank you for your help.
Well, it was my pleasure to extend my help
to the Ardiente family.
If that happened to me,
I wouldn't stop until justice was served.
And until I take back
what's only rightfully mine.
To Ivy Aguas.
For the Ardiente family.
-For the Ardiente family.
-Cheers.
Arnaldo.
I couldn't help but notice
you and Miss Aguas…
are growing closer.
Am I hearing wedding bells?
I'm not going to lie, Grandpa.
Someday, I want that firecracker
to be the mother of my children.
Firecracker? [chuckles]
A fitting description of this woman.
Interesting.
It seems like you're drunk
on love, or should I say…
lust?
That's why you're forgetting
about the whole set-up.
Set-up?
Come on, Arnaldo. Don't be stupid.
Because of your actions, you're
starting to look like a fool.
Or have you forgotten
Miss Aguas' transgressions
against our family?
[scoffs]
All right. What exactly are those?
-So far, all we have are doubts.
-Oh, come on, Arnaldo.
If anything, Grandpa…
We've proven her loyalty.
I don't understand
where your anger is coming from.
Watch your tone, young man--
How about you watch
your priorities, Congressman?
If you focus on this unfounded
suspicion against Ivy…
[scoffs] we're going to have a problem.
[upbeat music playing]
It's hot.
The weather or Miss Ivy Aguas?
Go on, Raul.
Try to say something I wouldn't like.
[Julio] Careful, Raul.
You're being watched by a hawk.
Emilia, the heat's unbearable, huh?
I know, Ivy.
But I have an even hotter scoop.
Is there something between you and my son?
Are you guys officially a couple?
Or is that fake news?
If it's true, what's wrong with that?
I'm single. So is Arnaldo.
If ever that happens,
we would be a hot couple.
We'd be hotter than summer.
You know, I just realized something.
Just when Papa started
to become suspicious of you,
why'd you cling to my son
like a jellyfish?
[chuckles]
Emilia, just a case of perfect timing.
Oh…
Some people have
a different term for it, though.
Perfect manipulation.
Are you calling me a manipulator?
[scoffs] Of course not!
But… you just know how to play
with the good people,
who you can benefit from.
As the saying goes,
"It takes one to know one."
Right?
But I won't allow my son
to be used by someone
who could betray our family.
Wait, I'm not saying
you're a traitor, okay?
It's purely hypothetical.
[dramatic music]
This is also hypothetical, Emilia.
This is hypothetical, okay?
What if I kill you right here?
Hmm?
Here! There you go.
[choking]
Well?
-Emilia!
-Serves you right!
You deserve to die!
-Ivy!
-I'm going to kill you.
-You're going to die.
-Ivy!
-Stay out of this!
-Stop it!
-Ivy, stop!
-I'm going to kill her!
-Stop it!
-Die, Emilia!
-Ivy!
-Stay out of this!
-Ivy! Ivy! Stop it, Ivy!
-Help me!
-Ivy!
-Get off me!
[groans]
Ivy, are you okay? You seem agitated.
[chuckles]
Well…
I know where you're coming from, Emilia.
But that's why I helped you
find Governor Alvarez
to prove my loyalty to your family.
As for me and Arnaldo,
we aren't official.
But once that happens,
I'll text you,
so you aren't late to the scoop.
Excuse me.
There's no turning back, Ivy.
I may be far away from you,
but you have my full support.
Who do you think is capable
of leading this town?
Aside from us, the Ardientes?
Me! I will run for governor
against you, Arnaldo!
[Arnaldo] You helped Diego.
[Ivy] May I just remind you, Mr. Mayor,
we aren't together
for you to feel jealous.
Mr. Mayor.
Out of my room!
-Do it again.
-Get out!
No, because I will keep
coming back for more.
Arnaldo!
[theme music playing]